Guide to the Oral History of the American Left Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Oral History of the American Left Main Series, 1940-2011
  - Pete Seeger, Feb 25, 1981; cuid1486 (Box 77, Cassette 224, Box 25, Cd Seeger 1)
    Seeger discusses the historical use of music as social protest, growing up in 1930s with folk music, the Communist Party song book, World War II, the blacklisting of artists during the 1950s, racism in America, and the Almanac Singers. Seeger performs songs at several junctures to illustrate his points, including union songs and a song about the Scottsboro Boys.
    See also CD's Prago 18-20 for recordings of Pete Seeger's contribution to Albert Prago's lecture series on the Spanish Civil War.
  - Berl Segal, May 4, 1977; cuid1487 (Box 25, Cd Berl Segal 1, Box 77, Cassette 225)
    Interview includes discussion of the Workmen's Circle in Providence, Rhode Island during the 1920s-40s, ethnic socialist groups in Providence, and the activities of the Socialist Party.
  - Bernard Segal, Jul 14, 1992; cuid1488 (Box 10, Cassette 412, Box 25, Cd B. Segal 1-2)
    Interview by Dorothy Fennel and Daniel Walkowitz.
  - Edith Segal, Feb 27, 1981; cuid1489 (Box 77, Cassette 226, Box 25, Cd E. Segal 1, Box 8, Folder 33)
    Segal discusses music and dance and the Left in the 1930s.
  - Irving Seid, Jun 4, 1976; cuid1490 (Box 25, Cd I. Seid 1-2, Box 77, Cassette 227 A)
    Seid discusses his New York background, the Depression and Unemployed Councils, and the effects of McCarthyism.
    interview by Danny Czistrom.
  - Tauhma Seid, Jul 4, 1976; cuid1491 (Box 25, Cd T. Seid 1-2, Box 77, Cassette 227 B)
    Seid discusses her youth in the Yorkville section of New York during the 1920s, cafeteria workers unionism, the Young Communist League, and the Communist Party during the 1940s-1950s.
    Interview by Danny Czitrom.
  - Leo Seidlitz, Jul 20, 1983; cuid1492 (Box 77, Cassette 229 A-B, Box 25, Cd Seidlitz 1-2)
    Interview includes discussion of Brooklyn College radical politics during the mid-1930s, Trotskyism during the late 1930s, the Workers Party during the 1940s, and the influence of Max Shachtman.
    Duration: 115 minutes in two parts
  - Leo Seidlitz, Aug 22, 1983; cuid1493 (Box 77, Cassette 232 B, Box 25, Cd Seidlitz 3)
    Interview regarding Workers Party.
    Duration: 73 minutes; Preservation note: drop outs at the beginning of each side
  - Les Sentinelles Oubliées: Eva and David Rosenberg and Jack and Erika Karan, Circa 1990; cuid1494 (Box 25, Cd Les Sentinelles Oubliees 1-3, Box 80, Cassette 331 A-D)
    Interviews with the Rosenbergs and Karans, taken for a French documentery titled Les Sentinelles Oubliées by Frédéric Rossif. Interviewees discuss their lives as Communists in 20th century America.
  - Nina Serrano, Nov 16, 1983; cuid1495 (Box 25, Cd Serrano 1, Box 77, Cassette 230)
    Interview contains Serrano's observations of middle-American culture as a Bohemian in Madison, Wisconsin during the in 1950s. She also discusses her recruitment into the Youth Labor League, her activities in the founding of the Peace Center, attendance at the Peace Festival in Moscow and travels in China, subsequent difficulty in school, Madison, and maintaining contact with friends from her time in Madison.
  - Mark Sharron, May 5, 1983; cuid1496 (Box 77, Cassette 231 A-C, Box 25, Cd Sharron 1-4)
    Interview covers various aspects of the Workers Party, Trotskyism, Workers' Party, Max Shachtman, and the Shachtmanite movement during the 1930s-1950s.
    Sharron discusses his travels with A.J. Muste through Holland and Paris in 1930s and a meeting with Leon Trostky in Norway. He also discusses his travels and experiences in Spain during Spanish Civil War and factionalism between different leftist elements, including the POUM, anarchists, and Stalinists. He details his interactions with POUM members and pro-Trotskyists and describes his arrest by anarchist leader on the Aragon front for affiliation with POUM. He also comments on the International Brigades, the Thalmanns, May Days, and reaction from others in the left when he returned to the United States.
    He describes a visit with Trotsky and Raya Dunayevskaya at Trotsky's home in Mexico in 1938. He also describes different wings of thought regarding Russian question, including the Johnsonites, Cannonites, and Shactmanites.
    Sharron then describes his service in Merchant Marine during World War II, and increasing involvement with the Workers Party. He analyzes the general outlook on on the Soviet Union during the second world war and impact on Workers Party politics in 1940s, particularly the San Francisco branch. He describes his travel to France after war and dissolution of marriage and analyzes the factions among the French Trotskyists.
    Sharron also discusses his life from the 1950s, including engineering work in Morocco doing contract work for air force starting in 1951, the FBI monitoring of the left, reflections on friendship and relationships in left politics, and his second career in therapy. He also describes his falling out with Shachtman after Sharron went to FBI to renounce connections with Fourth International.
    During the course of the interview, Bloom and Sharron refer to an earlier interview segment that the library no longer has record of.
    Interview by Jonathan Bloom at Tamiment Library.
  - Mark Sharron, Aug 19, 1983; cuid1497 (Box 77, Cassette 232 A-B, Box 25, Cd Sharron 5-7)
    Interview covers Sharron's childhood in Russia and Brownsville, his relationship with his family, his education at the City College of New York, the activities of the Young Communist League, his involvement with Trotskyism, his experiences in Europe, the activities of the Workers Party, and World War II.
  - Mark Sharron, Nov 10, 1983; cuid1498 (Box 77, Cassette 233 A-B, Box 25, Cd Sharron 8-9)
    Interview covers Sharron's activity in the Trotskyist movement during the 1930s-1940s, Trotskyism and questions of international socialism, and the character of the Workers Party.
    Duration: 46 minutes
  - John Shenton, Jun 20, 1967; cuid1499 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    Interview covers the activities of the Socialist Party in Bridgeport, Connecticut during the 1920s-1960s.
  - Moishe Shik, Dec 27, 1982; cuid1500 (Box 25, Cd Shik 1, Box 77, Cassette 234)
  - Anne Shore, May 12, 1982 - Jun 15, 1982; cuid1501 (Box 77, Cassette 235 A-H, Box 25, Cd Shore 1-8)
    Interview covers the activities of the Communist Party, the activities of the United Office and Professional Workers of America (UOPWA), picketing of the Nazi ship the Bremen, Shore's experiences in Detroit during the the 1940s, the Civil Rights Congress and Progressive Party in Los Angeles during the late 1940s through early 1950s, the effects of McCarthy period on the left, and Shore's work for Local 1199 (Hospital Workers) during the 1960s.
    Interview by Priscilla Backman.
  - Meyer Shticker, undated; cuid1502 (Box 10, Cassette 405, Box 25, Cd Shticker 1)
  - Elias Shulman, Oct 19, 1982; cuid1503 (Box 26, Cd Shulman 1, Box 79, Cassette 300)
  - Robert J. Silberstein and Howard Meyer, Jun 22, 1982; cuid1504 (Box 77, Cassette 236A-B, Box 26, Cd Silberstein and Meyer 1-2)
    Interview covers the activities International Labor Defense and the National Lawyers Guild from the 1930s-1940s.
  - Madeline Simon, Nov 15, 2002; cuid1505 (Box 26, Cd M. Simon 1-3, Box 8, Folder 35, Box 77, Cassette 237.1 A-B)
    Interview contains Simon's reminiscences on Camp Kinderland and a discussion of music and Yiddishkeit.
  - Fanny Simon, Feb 12, 1982; cuid1506
    Interview documents the activities of the Socialist Party during the 1930s.
    - Original recording, cuid43244 (Box 77, Audiocassette 237A)
    - Original recording, cuid43245 (Box 77, Audiocassette 237B)
      Preservation note: Audio is muted, side 2 is blank.
    - Access copies (Box 26, Cd F. Simon 1-2)
  - Donald Slaiman, Dec 16, 1994; cuid1507 (Box 26, Cd Slaiman 1, Box 80, Cassette 341)
  - Jessie Taft Smith, Nov 19, 1981; cuid1508 (Box 26, Cd Smith 1-3, Box 77, Cassette 238 A-B)
    Interview covers Smith's family background in Norwalk, Connecticut during the 1910s-1920s, the activities of the Young Communist League, the laundry workers' union, and Smith's social and political life in the 1930s.
  - Richard Soble, Mar 31, 1983; cuid1509 (Box 26, Cd Soble 1, Box 77, Cassette 239)
    Interview documents radical legal work in Detroit during the 1960s-1970s (including "Red Squad" lawsuit) and a late 1960s rent strike.
  - Socialist Labor Party, Mar 17, 1983; cuid1510 (Box 77, Cassette 240 A-D, Box 26, Cd Socialist Labor Party 1-4)
    Interview regarding Socialist Labor Party "South Slavonian" language federation during the 1920s-1950s in Detroit and Cleveland. Interviewees include John Brlas, Mary Petrovich-Brlas, Vito DeLisi, Mary Korach, and Matt Korach.
  - Southern Negro Youth Congress, Feb 6, 1984; cuid1511 (Box 26, Cd SNYC 1-2, Box 77, Cassette 241 A-B)
    Forum on the history of the Southern Negro Youth Congress featuring one-time SNYC activists Henry Winston, James Jackson, Grace Tillman Bassett, Esther Jackson, and Dorothy Burnham.
    Duration: 120 minutes in two parts
  - Spanish Civil War Poetry, Apr 8, 1980; cuid1512 (Box 10, Cassette data_value_missing_243a2f8cf606c6241c3945eb6aec3d5d, Box 26, Cd 418 A-B)
    Digital transfer of the the second side of the second cassette was not possible due to poor condition of the tape.
  - Anton Srok, Jul 26, 1983; cuid1513 (Box 26, Cd Srok 1-2, Box 77, Cassette 242 A-B)
    Interview covers the Srok's experiences in the Milwaukee Croatian Fraternal Union, 1930s-1980s and his labor activities in Milwaukee during 1930s. Srok also describes his experiences as an amateur Croatian-American actor in Milwaukee.
    Duration: 71 minutes in two parts
  - Sid Stein & Eugene Dennis, Dec 1957; cuid1514 (Box 80, Cassette 325, Box 26, Cd Stein 1)
    Speech by Sid Stein from a debate with Eugene Dennis at CPUSA Executive Committee.
  - Charlotte Stern, May 7, 1979; cuid1515 (Box 80, Cassette 330 A-B, Box 26, Cd C. Stern 1-2, Box 57)
    Interview regarding Stern's experiences as member of the executive board of Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee from 1944-1950. Second CD and cassette contains 2:56 of unrelated material on first track or side.
    Interview by Dorothy Swanson.
  - Sholem Stern, Sep 18, 1978; cuid1516 (Box 26, Cd S. Stern 1, Box 77, Cassette 243)
    Stern describes his experiences as a radical Yiddish writer and poet in Montreal and New York during the 1920s-1930s.
  - Sholem Stern, undated; cuid1517 (Box 10, Cassette 406, Box 26, Cd S. Stern 2)
    Discussion includes comments on Morgen Freiheit, Yiddishe Kultur, and other Yiddish literary outlets. Interview also includes discussion of prominent Yiddish writers and the relationship between literature, the Jewish left, and the Communist Party.
  - Morton Stavis, Dec 9, 1991 - Jan 21, 1992; cuid1518 (Box 80, Cassette 314 A-D, Box 26, Cd Stavis 1-4, Box 8, Folder 36)
    Topics discussed include Stavis' youth on the Lower East Side, education at City College and Columbia Law School, Social Security Administration, unionism and civil rights, working with Senator Wagner, the War Labor Board, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, Carl and Anne Braden, the Center for Constitutional Rights, and civil rights cases. Two specific cases covered are the McSurley Case of 1967 (regarding civil rights activists in Pikeville, Kentucky) and Philippines Case of 1986 (regarding property in New York owned by the the Marcos family).
    Interview by Alan Thomson.
  - Isidor Steuzert, Oct 27, 1982; cuid1519 (Box 26, Cd Steuzert 1, Box 77, Cassette 244)
    Interview documents the activities of the Jewish Socialist Federation, the nature of American Communism, and the Lovestoneites.
  - Chalmers Stewart, Jun 22, 1983; cuid1520 (Box 26, Cd Stewart 1, Box 10, Cassette 382)
    Interview contains Stewart's reflections on CLR James.
  - Chaim Suller, Jan 20, 1983; cuid1521 (Box 77, Cassette 245, Box 26, Cd Suller 1)
    Suller describes his background in the Jewish progressive movement and discusses the problems of the Morgen Freiheit in the 1980s.
    Duration: 40 minutes
  - Elliot Sullivan Memorial Service, undated; cuid1522 (Box 8, Folder 37, Box 10, Cd Sullivan 1, Box 26)
    Speakers at this recorded memorial service include Sylvia Thompson, Madeline Lee Gilford, Ralph Elswain, Ruby Dee, Will Lee, Biff Liff, Jane Hoffman, Peter Seeger, and Norma Sullivan.
  - Arne Swabeck, Apr 7, 1975 - Nov 19, 1975; cuid1523 (Box 77, Cassette 246A-G, Box 27, Cd Swabeck 1-51, Box 78, Cassette 246H-WW, Box 8, Folder 38, Box 28, Cd Swabeck 52-76)
    Series of tapes recorded by John Shannon in the course of researching for an unpublished book. Topics covered in this extensive set of interviews include: childhood, travels, Communist activities, analysis of factional splits in the left from the 1920s onward, and reflections on the left at the time of the interview.
    Interview by John Shannon.
    Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
    Digitization of this interview was not completed, due to the poor quality of the audio and size of the interview. Based on John Shannon's session notes for the interview, these issues likely date to the original recording. Cassettes 246A to 246OO have been digitized. Cassettes 246PP to 246WW have not been digitized.
    To request an access copy of materials in the undigitized portion of this interview, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.
    Original cassettes were donated to Columbia University's Oral History Research Office by John Shannon, and Columbia University also maintains a copy of the interview.
  - Arne Swabeck, Oct 23, 1982; cuid1524 (Box 28, Cd Swabeck 77-78, Box 77, Cassette 246 A-B)
    Interview covers the activities of the Scandinavian Socialist Federation and press.
    Duration: 98 minutes in two parts
  - A.O. Syrstad, Jan 5, 1978; cuid1525 (Box 28, Cd Syrstad 1, Box 78, Cassette 247)
    Interview documents the activities of the Workers Party and the Independent Socialist League in Seattle, Washington during the 1940s-1950s.
    Duration: 44 minutes
  - Loretta Szeliga, Dec 8, 1981; cuid1526 (Box 28, Cd Szeliga 1, Box 80, Cassette 354)
  - Anna Taffler, Jan 5, 1978; cuid1527 (Box 28, Cd Taffler 1-3, Box 8, Folder 45, Box 78, Cassette 248A-B)
    Taffler discusses the activities of the unemployed councils in Brooklyn between 1930 and 1934.
  - Stephen Tendler, Oct 5, 1984; cuid1528 (Box 10, Cassette 411, Box 28, Cd Tendler 1)
    Topics discussed include the activities of the Socialist Labor Party in Saint Louis from the 1930s-1960s, the Bulgarian Federation in Granite City, Illinois, and the reorganization of Section Saint Louis in 1979.
  - Norman Thomas, 1960; cuid1529 (Box 8, Folder 39/40/41/42)
    Interview contains the reminiscences of Norman Thomas, the six-time Socialist Party candidate for President.
    Interview by Harry Fleischman.
  - Norman Thomas, Nov 17, 1966; cuid1530 (Box 8, Folder 39/40/41/42)
    Interview contains Thomas' recollections of Jasper McLevy, the Socialist Mayor of Bridgeport, Connecticut from 1933-1957.
  - Norman Thomas 1932 Campaign, 50th Anniversary, Nov 19, 1982 - Nov 20, 1982; cuid1531 (Box 28, Cd Thomas Campaign 1-6, Box 78, Cassette 251 A-F)
    This recording of a reunion includes speakers Ruth Senior, Mickey Most, Herb Wolfe, John Herling, Noah Walter, and Michael Harrington. Speakers share their recollections of Thomas' first presidential campaign and discuss his career and influence overall.
  - Debate between Norman Thomas and Barry Goldwater, 1961; cuid1532 (Box 10, Cassette 414, Box 28, Cd Thomas and Goldwater 1)
  - Bessie Thomashow, undated; cuid1533 (Box 28, Cd Thomasow 1, Box 78, Cassette 253)
    Interview documents the activities of the Workmen's Circle during the 1930s.
  - Fred Thompson, Apr 1983; cuid1534 (Box 28, Cd Thompson 3-4, Box 78, Cassette 255)
    Interview regarding the activities of the International Workers of the World after 1924.
    Duration: 89 minutes
  - Fred Thompson, Jul 26, 1983; cuid1535 (Box 28, Cd Thompson 1-2, Box 8, Folder 43, Box 78, Cassette 254 A-B)
    Interview includes an analysis of the nature of the language federations attached to Industrial Workers of the World, descriptions of prominent immigrant figures in IWW, and commentary on the eclipse of the language federations and ethnic press in the IWW.
    Duration: 87 minutes in two parts
  - Alan Thomson, Feb 11, 1993; cuid1536 (Box 80, Cassette 327 A-B, Box 28, Cd Thomson 1-3)
    Interview by Stacy Sewell.
  - Ahrne Thorne, Dec 15, 1983; cuid1537 (Box 8, Folder 44, Box 28, Cd Thorne 1-2, Box 78, Cassette 256 A-B)
    Interview documents Thorne's background in Poland, his education as an anarchist, Yiddish anarchism in the United States since the 1920s, the relationship between Yiddish anarchism and Zionism, and Thorne's recollections of Rudolf Rocker.
  - Ahrne Thorne, undated; cuid1538 (Box 10, Cassette 407, Box 28, Cd Thorne 3)
  - Frank Trager, Nov 21, 1973; cuid1539 (Box 28, Cd Trager 1-2, Box 80, Cassette 338)
    Duration: 98 minutes
  - Haunani-Kay Trask, undated; cuid1540 (Box 28, Cd Trask 1-2, Box 79, Cassette 303 A-B)
    Interview by Joy Shimabukuro
  - Jerry Trauber, Nov 4, 1979; cuid1541 (Box 10, Cassette 408, Box 28, Cd Trauber 1)
  - Esther Travaglio, Oct 30, 1982; cuid1542 (Box 78, Cassette 257 A-B, Box 29, Cd Travaglio 1-2)
    Interview documents the background and activities of Esther Hartz Travaglio. It also covers the activities of "Gene" Travaglio, an anarchist and job-printer in Seattle and California.
  - Jean Tussey, Oct 24, 1978 - Oct 25, 1978, Mar 20, 1979; cuid1543 (Box 8, Folder 46/47, Box 29, Cd Tussey 1-4, Box 78, Cassette 259 A-C)
    Interview covers Tussey's activities with the Steel Workers Organizing Committee, the Socialist Party, and the Socialist Workers Party in New Jersey and Southern California from the 1930s through the early 1940s.
    Interview by Debra Bernhardt and Jon Bloom.
    Duration: 111 minutes in two parts; Preservation Note: The third audiocassette could not be digitized due to its condition.
  - Uhro Tuominen, Nov 5, 1983; cuid1544 (Box 78, Cassette 258, Box 29, Cd Tuuominen 1)
    Interview documents the activities of the "younger" generation of Finnish-American radicals in Midwest and California. Tuominen describes of the tenacity and decline of Finnish-American activity in Bay Area and the effort of Communist and non-Communist Finnish-Americans to engage in common functions.
    Duration: 64 minutes; Preservation note: Poor audio quality
  - Gus Tyler, Oct 29, 1973; cuid1545 (Box 80, Cassette 339 A-B, Box 29, Cd Tyler 1-2)
    Duration: 78 minutes in two parts
  - Tyomies Panel Discussion, Jul 30, 1983; cuid1546 (Box 29, Cd Tyomies 1-2, Box 78, Cassette 260)
    Panel discussion including Mary Kolehmainen, Helen Kruth, Ernest Koski and other prominent editorial workers on the origins, development, and continuation of Finnish-language newspaper Tyomies (The Worker) and its sister paper Naisten Viiri (Women's Banner). Presentation includes history of paper, government intimidation of newspaper, achievements of Finnish-American press and people, the decline of the circulation, and the development of cooperative movements.
    Discussion recorded by Paul Buhle.
  - Unemployed Organizations of the 1930s, Apr 30, 1983; cuid1547 (Box 29, Cd Unemployed Organizations 1-3, Box 78, Cassette 261 A-B)
    A recording of a session of a 1983 New York State Labor History Association meeting. Includes a presentation by Roy Rosenzweig, followed by panel discussion with Saul Parker, John Gates, Rose Schuyler, and Brendan Sexton.
  - Unidentified Yiddish-language Poet (originally from Ukraine), Mar 21, 1979; cuid1548 (Box 29, Cd Unidentified Poet 1, Box 10, Cassette 390)
    Narrator speaks about youth in Ukraine and Romania, introduction to poetry, influences (including Russian, Native American, African American, and Roma poetry), his books Flowers in the Snow and Eternally Green, the influence of Marxism on his poetry, and Moshe Nadir.
  - Willard Uphaus and Ruth MacLennan, Jul 20, 1983; cuid1549 (Box 29, Cd Uphaus 1-2, Box 79, Cassette 304 A-B)
    Interview documents the lives of Willard and Ruth MacLennan Uphaus, with a special emphasis on their activities in the 1930s. Topics include their meeting, the intersection of their politics and Christianity, their friendship with Claude Williams, and Socialism.
  - Willard Uphaus, Nov 9, 1980; cuid1550 (Box 29, Cd Uphaus 3-4, Box 79, Cassette 262 A-B)
    Recording of Willard Uphaus' 90th birthday celebration, by Bea Lemisch.
  - Vittorio Vidali, Aug 6, 1981; cuid1551 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    Interview covers the activities of the Italian Language Federation and the American Communist movement during the 1920s, Chicago and the Left, and Vidali's reflections on American Communism. Translated from the Italian-language Autobiography of Vittorio Vidali, a document on his years in the United States from 1923 to 1927.
  - Abraham Vishnu & Getzel Becker, Oct 25, 1978; cuid1552 (Box 29, Cd Vishnu & Becker 1, Box 79, Cassette 264 A-B)
    Interview documents radicalism and culture in New York and Miami Beach, anti-Semitism in the radical movements of Poland, life for Jewish workers in pre-revolutionary Cuba, and the importance of Yiddish culture for political movements from the 1920s-1950s.
    Duration: 124 minutes in two parts; Preservation note: Poor audio quality
  - Jacob Waisbord, Jun 28, 1993; cuid1553 (Box 29, Cd Waisbord 1-3, Box 80, Cassette 340 A-B)
    Interview regarding the Left Poale Zion and the Jewish Labor Committee.
    Interview by Gail Malmgreen.
  - Hershel Walker, undated; cuid1554 (Box 29, Cassette Walker 1-2, Box 80, Cassette 356-357)
  - Frank Wallin, Jul 31, 1983; cuid1555 (Box 79, Cassette 266, Box 29, Cd Wallin 1)
    Interview documents Wallin's editorial activities from the 1940s-1970s for the Finnish-language paper Tyomies and Industrilistii,, a Finnish-American newspaper affiliated with the International Workers of the World (IWW).
  - Albert Warner, May 4-5, 1980; cuid1556 (Box 79, Cassette 305 A-B, Box 29, Cd Warner 1-2)
  - Susan Warren - Transcript, Apr 17, 1966; cuid1557 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Interview documents the activities of the Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy and the Jefferson School of Social Science during the 1950s.
  - Arthur Waskow, Apr 2, 1970; cuid1558 (Box 29, Cd Waskow 1, Box 79, Cassette 276)
    Interview describes activities and internal politics of Students for a Democratic Society. Waskow reflects on its eventual dissolution.
  - Mary-Alice Waters, undated; cuid1559 (Box 29, Cd Waters 1, Box 79, Cassette 267)
    A recording of Mary-Alice Waters' speech titled "Women's Liberation and the Socialist Revolution."
  - Stan Weir, Dec 28, 1981; cuid1560 (Box 79, Cassette 269 A-B, Box 29, Cd Weir 1-2)
    Interview document's Weir's experiences in Los Angeles.
  - Stan Weir, Aug 13, 1983 - Aug 15, 1983; cuid1561 (Box 29, Cd Weir 5-14, Box 79, Cassette 269 E-J)
  - Stan Weir, Oct 22, 1982; cuid1562 (Cassette 269A-M, Box 29, Cd Weir 3-4, Box 79, Cassette 269 C-D)
    Interview documents Weir's analyses of the activities of C.L.R. James, the Johnson-Forest Tendency, and the Workers Party.
  - Myra Tanner Weiss, 1982; cuid1563 (Box 79, Cassette 270, Box 29, Cd Weiss 1)
    Interview covers Weiss' family and educational background in Salt Lake City and Los Angeles, the unemployed movement and Trotskyist movement during the 1930s-1940s, anti-fascist demonstrations, and her experiences as Socialist Workers Party candidate during the 1940s-1950s.